### **ABHAY KUMAR YADAV**

Mob. No.- +917834912988

E-mail ID:abhay971825@gmail.com

#### **SYNOPSIS:**

I am smart-working and committed to assignments given to me. I always like the situation which give me total exposure of my talents and knowledge and I have an aptitude to come across the varieties of situations including the problems which add to my experience and knowledge. I desire to achieve and have willingness to learn. My aim is to become an expert in focused area.

#### **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION:**

XII from U.P. BOARD with SCIENCE STREAM.

X from U.P. BOARD with SCIENCE STREAM.

## **PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION:**

(B.C.A) Bachelor of Computer Application from Chaudhary Charan Singh University, Meerut.

## **EXTRA QUALIFICATION:**

DIPLOMA IN 2D ANIMATION from OSCAR SOFTWARE INSTITUTE.

### **SOFTWARE SKILLS:**

Video Software:- Adobe Flash, After Effects, lectora & Articulate, Vyond,

Audio Software: - Sony Sound Forge, Adobe Audition

Design Software:- Illustrator, Photoshop,

Other Software: - MS WORD, POWERPOINT & EXCEL

TYPING SPEED (ENGLISH) - 20-25 WPM

### **AREA OF INTEREST:**

Paper work sketching designing and any art creating in blank chart paper.

2D animation designing in flash.

## **JOB PROFILE:**

2d Character Creator, Layout Designer & Storyboarding.

Co-ordination with other departments to collect information.

Maintaining of files in systematic manners.

# **WORKING EXPERIENCE:**

Organization	Project	Post	Duration
Wings Multimedia Solutions	NIIT Project	Object Animator	18 Jun 2011 - 10 Nov 2012
Screwdriver Film Production	Viva Prakashan, Protegent Antivirus	Character Animator	12 Nov 2012 - 09 Jan 2014
Trihedron Infotech Ltd	K-12 Project	Character Animator	10 Jan 2014 - 31 Jan 2015
Educity Pedagogy Pvt Ltd	BSC Academy	Character Animator	13 Apr 2015 - 12 Mar 2016
Satya Bhawna Production	Oxford, MAGIC (Pearson, Madhuban)	Character Animator	18 Jul 2016 – 03 Apr 2017
360 Degree Info-Dynamics Pvt. Ltd.	IIIEYE VMS, Hook- Knowledge	Character Animator	04 Apr 2017 - Aug 2019

# .PROJECT WORK:

Eklavya: Online / Education, Project by NIIT

**Viva Aviral:** Create E-Learning Booksin Adobe Flash.

Viva Pankhudi: Create E-Learning Booksin Adobe Flash.

**Protegent Antivirus:** 2d Character Create, Storyboarding and animation.

**AIMS (Echocardiography):** Create and modify videos for aims hospital.

K12 projects: Class 1to12th

**Bank PO:** Banking Exam Preparation, E-Learning CD.

Blueprint Education's: Create E-Learning Booksin Adobe Flash.

**OXFORD:** Story and Poems

MAGIC (Madhuban): Story and Poems

MAGIC (Pearson): Story and Poems

MASTERMINDS (Butterscotch): Create E-Learning Booksin Adobe Flash.

# **KEY SKILLS:**

Ability to work as a team member.

Eager to learn.

Have good inter-personal skills & flexible in all working environment

## **STRENGTH:**

Positive attitude.

Passion to facing challenges.

Dedicated to hard work.

Punctual and Disciplined.

Quick in learning from mistakes.

## **PERSONAL DETAILS:**

Father's Name Sh. Shiv Prakash Yadav

Permanent Address E-143D, Pratap Vihar, Sector-12 Ghaziabad.201009

Correspondence Address Villeg – Dangata, Post -Bahlolpur Distt. – Pratapgarh (U.P.).

Date of Birth 23/04/1991

Sex Male
Nationality Indian
Marital Status Unmarried
Language Known Hindi & English

# **DECLARATION:**

I hereby solemnly declare that the above given particulars are true to the best of my knowledge.